<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Legals on </title>
    <link>https://toddr.org/legal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Legals on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="https://toddr.org/legal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Estimate Terms</title>
      <link>https://toddr.org/legal/estimates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toddr.org/legal/estimates/</guid>
      <description>By accepting the terms of an estimate sent by Todd Rylaarsdam, the client agrees to pay the specified fees and rates for the work described in the estimate. Any additional work not covered in this estimate will incur additional charges, which will be discussed prior to the start of work. Payment terms may vary on a per-client basis but are typically net 30 days.
Any changes requested by the client to quantities, specifications, schedule, or other aspects of the services described in an estimate are not binding unless accepted by Todd Rylaarsdam in writing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>https://toddr.org/legal/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toddr.org/legal/privacy/</guid>
      <description>At Todd Rylaarsdam, accessible from toddr.org, one of our main priorities is the privacy of our visitors. This Privacy Policy document contains types of information that is collected and recorded by Todd Rylaarsdam and how we use it.
If you have additional questions or require more information about our Privacy Policy, do not hesitate to contact us.
This Privacy Policy applies only to our online activities and is valid for visitors to our website with regards to the information that they shared and/or collect in Todd Rylaarsdam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terms of Service</title>
      <link>https://toddr.org/legal/tos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toddr.org/legal/tos/</guid>
      <description>OVERVIEW
This website is operated by Todd Rylaarsdam. Throughout the site, the terms “we”, “us” and “our” refer to Todd Rylaarsdam. Todd Rylaarsdam offers this website, including all information, tools and services available from this site to you, the user, conditioned upon your acceptance of all terms, conditions, policies and notices stated here.
By visiting our site and/ or purchasing something from us, you engage in our “Service” and agree to be bound by the following terms and conditions (“Terms of Service”, “Terms”), including those additional terms and conditions and policies referenced herein and/or available by hyperlink.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
