<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>https://toddr.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://toddr.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Play that Goes Wrong (Asst. Sound Designer)</title>
      <link>https://toddr.org/productions/play-that-goes-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toddr.org/productions/play-that-goes-wrong/</guid>
      <description>Completed: 2023-03-17 | George Fox University | Roles: Asst. Sound Designer, Master Sound Technician, Scenic Construction</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oliver (Mix Engineer)</title>
      <link>https://toddr.org/productions/oliver/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toddr.org/productions/oliver/</guid>
      <description>Completed: 2022-11-12 | George Fox University | Roles: Mix Engineer, Master Sound Technician, Scenic Construction</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignment Canvas v2</title>
      <link>https://toddr.org/projects/assignment-canvas-v2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toddr.org/projects/assignment-canvas-v2/</guid>
      <description>Completed: 2022-07-03 | Personal Project
This is a version 2 of the old Assignment Canvas I built back in 2021 (learn more about that here). This new and improved version adds a bunch of stuff the old one didn&amp;rsquo;t have, like viewing assignments in detail, external linking to Canvas, an easier setup process, and a new responsive UI. You can give it a try at canvas.toddr.org
I also made an Android app using Kotlin and Jetpack Compose that interacts with the Assignment Canvas API to let you view your account and feed from your phone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>eHealth Platform</title>
      <link>https://toddr.org/projects/ehealth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toddr.org/projects/ehealth/</guid>
      <description>Completed: 2022-07-01 | Client: Mayo Clinic | Employer: Windy City Lab
The EHealth system was part of a contract for Mayo Clinic&amp;rsquo;s BNEL (Bioelectronics Neurophysiology and Engineering) laboratory. Their focus is on patients with chronic epilepsy and seizures and using brain implants to try and detect and disrupt these events preemptively.
WCL was originally only responsible for building an iOS and watchOS app for EHealth, however this transformed into a whole suite of tools that I was a part of building.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Snippets</title>
      <link>https://toddr.org/projects/code-snippets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toddr.org/projects/code-snippets/</guid>
      <description>Completed: 2022-06-15 | Personal Project
After Windy City Lab switched over to using Discord for internal communication, we encountered a problem when sharing code: discord has a 2000 character limit for messages unless you subscribe to their Nitro plan. This meant that if you wanted to share a large code snippet, you had to either break it up into multiple messages, or upload it as a file. Neither of these options were ideal, so I decided to make a web app to solve this problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kimball &amp; Bean Nameplates</title>
      <link>https://toddr.org/projects/kimball-bean/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toddr.org/projects/kimball-bean/</guid>
      <description>Completed: 2022-04-30 | Client: Kimball &amp;amp; Bean for The White House | Employer: Windy City Lab
This was a project from Kimball &amp;amp; Bean (makers of fancy custom planters and other garden ornaments) to manufacture branded nameplates to be used on a small run of planters destined for the first lady&amp;rsquo;s office in the White House.
The plates were supposed to be ~5in x 1in, so the details present in their logo would be tricky to recreate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS Training Event (AV Design)</title>
      <link>https://toddr.org/productions/aws-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toddr.org/productions/aws-training/</guid>
      <description>Completed: 2022-04-27 | Bosch | Roles: AV Design, AV Technician</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ANL Gen3 Soil Sensors</title>
      <link>https://toddr.org/projects/anl-gen3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toddr.org/projects/anl-gen3/</guid>
      <description>Completed: 2022-03-01 | Client: Argonne National Laboratory | Employer: Windy City Lab
I worked on this project at Windy City Lab as a full time intern there. This project included a lot of different components, from PCB design (including RF filtering and amplification) to 3d enclosure modeling to API work in Node.JS. The premise of the project was that Argonne National Laboratory along with the University of Chicago wanted to have a fleet of 150 soil sensors (motes) buried underground for 4 years on battery, wirelessly transmitting the data they read from their various sensors to the cloud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launch Chicago LMS</title>
      <link>https://toddr.org/projects/launch-chicago/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toddr.org/projects/launch-chicago/</guid>
      <description>Completed: 2021-12-12 | Employer: Windy City Lab
This project was for an initiative of Windy City Lab called Launch Chicago. Launch wanted a learning management system (LMS) to facilitate their hybrid approach to teaching Swift, app development, and computer science, but nothing available on the market was really a good fit for the coding focued classwork.
I worked on this app for a few months, first designing the data structures to store course content, user data, and results in, and then adding in both student and teacher/administrator UIs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ANL Connect</title>
      <link>https://toddr.org/projects/anl-connect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toddr.org/projects/anl-connect/</guid>
      <description>Completed: 2021-10-25 | Client: Argonne National Laboratory | Employer: Windy City Lab
ANL Connect controls and configures Gen3 Gemini series underground soil sensors built by Windy City Lab for Argonne National Labs. Currently the app is only available for Android, but there are plans to add iOS support in the future.
The app uses low energy bluetooth (BLE) to communicate with the testing devices. Since we want to make sure everything is working as expected during our testing, the protocol that the app uses to communicate over BLE is very robust and filled with confirmations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TCHS Chapels (Livestream, Sound)</title>
      <link>https://toddr.org/productions/tchs-chapels/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toddr.org/productions/tchs-chapels/</guid>
      <description>Completed: 2021-05-30 | Timothy Christian High School | Roles: Co-Tech Director, Mix Engineer, AVL System Tech, Lighting Designer</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignment Canvas v1</title>
      <link>https://toddr.org/projects/assignment-canvas-v1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toddr.org/projects/assignment-canvas-v1/</guid>
      <description>Completed: 2021-03-15 | Personal Project
Checkout the v2 of this project
Tapping directly into the Canvas API, Assignment Canvas organizes all your announcements and assignments from all your courses into one central location. No more clicking through a dozen courses to find all your homework. Users simply enter an access token that is authorized to only read data from their account, and they&amp;rsquo;re up and running.
Assignment Canvas was created when my school switched to Canvas as their LMS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spacebot Sensor Enclosure</title>
      <link>https://toddr.org/projects/spacebot-enclosure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toddr.org/projects/spacebot-enclosure/</guid>
      <description>Completed: 2020-11-10 | Client: Spacebot | Employer: Windy City Lab
This was a project for SpaceBot, a startup that focuses on helping companies study how people use their spaces and offices. They use environmental and visual sensors to detect space usage in real time and show that to users in a web dashboard.
My work focused on designing a new enclosure for both their environmental &amp;ldquo;kit&amp;rdquo; and visual kit. Design requirements like PoE compatibility, an adjustable camera mount, mounting for a Raspberry Pi 4 as well as an SSD were taken into consideration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scholastic Bowl Bot</title>
      <link>https://toddr.org/projects/scholastic-bot/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toddr.org/projects/scholastic-bot/</guid>
      <description>Completed: 2020-11-10 | Personal Project
A discord bot that enables virtual scholastic bowl competitions. Created in the age of COVID, this bot keeps track of buzzes and manages players in a discord voice chat.
The scholastic bowl bot lets schools host virtual scholastic bowl competitions. By simply inviting the bot to a discord server and creating a few roles and voice channels, teams can run competitions, play local scrimages, and also benefit from the various community features in discord.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CPU Emulator</title>
      <link>https://toddr.org/projects/cpu-emulator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toddr.org/projects/cpu-emulator/</guid>
      <description>Completed: 2020-07-20 | Employer: Windy City Lab
Capable of powering 32 physical and unlimited virtual CPU components, and creating a network-based 8 or 16 bit CPU. Using a combination of custom PCBs and breadboards as well as the Emulator, you can create your own custom CPU right on your desk.
The emulator supports up to 32 hardware components that interface with a Particle microcontroller over a custom PCB. Components can be built by hand on a breadboard, or made on custom PCBs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TCHS Octoberfest (Lighting)</title>
      <link>https://toddr.org/productions/octoberfest/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toddr.org/productions/octoberfest/</guid>
      <description>Completed: 2019-09-26 | Timothy Christian High School | Roles: Lighting Designer/Operator</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://toddr.org/description/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toddr.org/description/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Todd Rylaarsdam, a software developer focused on the internet of things.
I&amp;rsquo;m currently a student at George Fox University studying computer science.
This summer I&amp;rsquo;m working with the Mayo Clinic&amp;rsquo;s BNEL lab as an embedded software intern.
Previously I worked as an embedded software development and hardware engineering intern for a year and a half at Windy City Lab.
You can find me and my work on GitHub (@trylaarsdam), LinkedIn, and Google Developers (@rylaarsdam).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Todd</title>
      <link>https://toddr.org/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toddr.org/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently a student at George Fox University studying computer science. Before that I worked as a embedded software development and hardware engineering intern for about a year and a half at Windy City Lab. Most of my personal work is available on GitHub @trylaarsdam, and you can read some more about projects I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on on the projects page.
For software development, I have experience making apps and backends with JavaScript and Node.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Me</title>
      <link>https://toddr.org/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toddr.org/contact/</guid>
      <description>Via Email Product Support: support@toddr.org
General Questions: todd@toddr.org
Social Media GitHub: @trylaarsdam
GitLab: @trylaarsdam
LinkedIn: @trylaarsdam
Google Developers: @rylaarsdam</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Estimate Terms</title>
      <link>https://toddr.org/legal/estimates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toddr.org/legal/estimates/</guid>
      <description>By accepting the terms of an estimate sent by Todd Rylaarsdam, the client agrees to pay the specified fees and rates for the work described in the estimate. Any additional work not covered in this estimate will incur additional charges, which will be discussed prior to the start of work. Payment terms may vary on a per-client basis but are typically net 30 days.
Any changes requested by the client to quantities, specifications, schedule, or other aspects of the services described in an estimate are not binding unless accepted by Todd Rylaarsdam in writing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>https://toddr.org/legal/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toddr.org/legal/privacy/</guid>
      <description>At Todd Rylaarsdam, accessible from toddr.org, one of our main priorities is the privacy of our visitors. This Privacy Policy document contains types of information that is collected and recorded by Todd Rylaarsdam and how we use it.
If you have additional questions or require more information about our Privacy Policy, do not hesitate to contact us.
This Privacy Policy applies only to our online activities and is valid for visitors to our website with regards to the information that they shared and/or collect in Todd Rylaarsdam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>https://toddr.org/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toddr.org/resume/</guid>
      <description>Todd Rylaarsdam Software Developer, Embedded Hardware Engineer +1 (331) 551-1758 | todd@toddr.org | Download as a PDF
Skills Javascript/NodeJS - 2 years of full-time professional experience Embedded C/C++ - 2 years of full-time professional experience PCB Design - 1.5 years of full-time professional experience Databases - 2 years of experience with NoSQL databases like Firestore and InfluxDB 3D CAD (Solidworks, Onshape, Inventor) - 1 year of experience Experience Windy City Lab - Full-Time Software Development Intern</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terms of Service</title>
      <link>https://toddr.org/legal/tos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toddr.org/legal/tos/</guid>
      <description>OVERVIEW
This website is operated by Todd Rylaarsdam. Throughout the site, the terms “we”, “us” and “our” refer to Todd Rylaarsdam. Todd Rylaarsdam offers this website, including all information, tools and services available from this site to you, the user, conditioned upon your acceptance of all terms, conditions, policies and notices stated here.
By visiting our site and/ or purchasing something from us, you engage in our “Service” and agree to be bound by the following terms and conditions (“Terms of Service”, “Terms”), including those additional terms and conditions and policies referenced herein and/or available by hyperlink.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
